Guide to the Journal of Sir Simonds d'Ewes (Transcripts)
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Journal of Sir Simonds d'Ewes (transcripts)
1642-1645
MS 1987
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of typewritten transcripts of the journal of Sir Simonds d'Ewes (1602-1650), First Baronet and member of the Long Parliament (1640-1648) for Sudbury in Suffolk. The transcripts are for volumes 4-6, the unpublished volumes of d'Ewes' journal, and are dated from September 1642 to November 1645. The journals were transcribed and edited by Anne Steele Young, co-editor of The Private Journals of the Long Parliament.
D'Ewes, Simonds, Sir, 1602-1650
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale Center for Parliamentary History, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Sir Simonds d'Ewes (1602-1650) was a British politician, First Baronet, and member of the Long Parliament for Sudbury in Suffolk. D'Ewes was educated at St. John's College, Cambridge, and studied under Richard Holdsworth. Though he was called to the English Bar as a barrister in 1623, d'Ewes did not pursue a legal career, and instead pursued a career as an antiquarian. In 1639 d'Ewes became High Sheriff of Suffolk, and was elected to the Long Parliament the following year. He was given a baronetcy by the King in 1641. At the outbreak of the English Civil War, d'Ewes joined the Parliamentarians (also known as "Roundheads"), and he remained a member of parliament until 1648 when he was expelled as part of Pride's Purge. Following the purge, d'Ewes left politics for good and devoted the remainder of his life to his work as an antiquarian, for which he was very well known.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of typewritten transcripts of the journal of Sir Simonds d'Ewes (1602-1650), First Baronet and member of the Long Parliament (1640-1648) for Sudbury in Suffolk. The transcripts are for volumes 4-6, the unpublished volumes of d'Ewes' journal, and are dated from September 1642 to November 1645. The journals were transcribed and edited by Anne Steele Young, co-editor of The Private Journals of the Long Parliament.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1642-1649; D'Ewes, Simonds, Sir, 1602-1650; Great Britain. Parliament -- History
- Inventory, 2002
  - Volume IV part 1, 1642 September 19-December 26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Volume IV part 2, 1643 January 13-March 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Volume IV part 3, 1643 April 1-June 29 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Volume IV part 4, 1643 July 1-September 23 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Volume IV part 5, 1643 October 28-December 31 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Volume V part 1, 1644 January 1-April 30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Volume V part 2, 1644 May 1-August 31 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Volume V part 3, 1644 September 2-December 24 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Volume VI part 1, 1645 January 7-May 31 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Volume VI part 2, 1645 June 2-November 3 (Box 5, Folder 2)